## About Me

## Summary

I'm an experienced .NET web application developer, who has been working in several enterprise applications since 2015, with a fine knowledge of Database Design, Design Pattern, Object-Oriented Programming.

I have a solid experience in ASP.NET Web Form and ASP.NET MVC technologies, as well as JavaScript, TypeScripts, Twitter Bootstrap, Materialize CSS and responsive web design. I also have knowledge about distributed programming with WCF, Web APIs and efficient development modal like Agile - Scrum. My English skill is fluent with IELTS 6.0, certificated since April 2016.

Beside Full-Stack web developer role, I've also been a Team Leader and Scrum Master.

I like to help and learn from other members, good in teamwork and communication. I am also eager to learn and tend to work well within a group.



### Personal Details

Full name: *Duong Nhat Minh* 

Alias: Minh Duong

Job title: *Full stack developer* 

Marital Status: Single

Email: minhduongnhat@outlook.com

Skype ID: minhdn1102Mobile: +84 976 716 296

Website: https://minhdn2.github.io/

### Skills

### Programming Languages

- C# .NET, .NET Core
- HTML 5, CSS3, SCSS
- JavaScript
- TypeScript

### Framework & Platforms

- Angular 2+ / ReactJS
- JQuery / Twitter Bootstrap / Materialize
  - CSS
- ASP.NET MVC / Entity Framework / LINQ to SQL / ADO.NET
- ASP.NET Web API / RestfulAPI / JSON, XML
- WCF
- ASP.NET Core

### IDF

- Git (Github & Gitlab)

Version Control

- Visual Studio
- Visual Code

#### Database

- Microsoft SQL Server
- MySQL
- Basic Knowledge of MongoDB

## Foreign Language

- TOEIC 750/900 (recorded 2017)

- Team Foundation
   Server (TFS)
- SVN (Tortoise SVN)

Brackets

- IELTS 6.0 (recorded April 2016)

## Knowledge / Other Skills

- Been a Team Leader and Scrum Master
- Good understanding and familiar with Agile and Scrum process
- Familiar with Unit testing
- Deep understanding about OOP, Design Pattern, SOLID principles, Dependency Injection, ...
- Familiar with Clean Code and Code Refactoring
- Good understanding about software design, database design, system design, Restful API
- Good time management, presentation, and teamwork skills

# **Experiences**

## **Career Summary**

- Working with .NET projects for enterprise since 2015.
- Have strong knowledge of web-based application, software design, Windows Service, Web API.
- Fluent in English communication IELTS 6.0 since April 2016.
- Familiar with Agile, Scum projects.
- Working in many OSDC projects. Working directly with customers.

## Employment History – Work Experiences

Ascentis	
Position: Scrum Master / Full Stack Developer	
Duration: March 2020 - Present	
Company: Ascentis	
Team Size: Multiple Teams, 2 to 7 members each team	
Description	Ascentis is one of the top companies that specialize in providing CRM – CMS solution integrated with Ecommerce. The company has a vast amount of clients in the eCommerce industry.
	I've been working for Ascentis since March 2020. From March 2020
	until November 2021 was working for Ascentis under CMC Global. From
	November 2021 to present, I've been working directly with Ascentis.
Responsibilities	I have a chance to work on multiple projects for multiple clients. Most of my time here I was designated to the BAU team. The purpose of this team is to maintain and execute the change requests for the large amount of projects from the clients of Ascentis.
	I was the Full-Stack web developer and Scrum Master for this team.  During my time here, my responsibilities are:

Step by step, sprint by sprint, to build the Scrum process for the team, so that the process is there to help the team working effectively, not blocking their way Make sure the process is reasonable and well adapted by other team members Make sure all members understand the process and comfortable while following that process Make sure the team is proactive in getting advise / explanation about the task assigned Helping team members to resolve blockers Code review Fix bugs, implement updates or change request Deploy to UAT to verify, request for deployment on Production and verify Working with BA, developers, PO and testers from other teams, make sure the changes are implemented correctly as the requirements and work smoothly, not break any other business after released Asp.NET Web Form **Project Technologies** Asp.NET MVC .NET Core / .NET 6 HTML, CSS, SCSS, JQuery, JavaScript, TypeScript ReactJS Team Foundation Server (TFS) with CI/CD SQL Server **PostgreSQL** Hangfire **Orchard Core** 

A St	A Startup for E-Commerce and payment solutions		
Position: Team Lead / Full Sta	Position: Team Lead / Full Stack Developer		
Duration: August 2019 – Mai	rch 2020		
Company: ITE			
Team Size: 8 members			
	The company is a startup company, focused on building product		
Description	applications, with the business domain is about handling the payment		
	process for e-commerce websites. The company's business strategy is		
	to aim to the e-commerce enterprises those in need of integrating		
	online payment methods.		
	During my short time working here, I was both a team leader and the		
	main front-end developer. I was also working on multiple projects at a		
	time.		
	I have gone through three projects here, which are:		
	- a Landing Page working as a gateway to routing customer to		
	the payment gateway of the payment type they choose		
	- an Admin Management System that allows the administrators		
	to manage the customers' information, their transactions, the		
	sales information,		
	They are all built using Angular 8, Angular Material and some other		
	libraries for front-end, and .Netcore Web API / Java Web API for the		
	back-end.		
	My responsibilities and what I have done during the time I worked here		
Responsibilities	are:		
	- Help BA to design mockup UI		
	<ul> <li>Help BA to clarify and build requirements</li> </ul>		
	<ul> <li>Design working process for everybody</li> </ul>		
	- Design business flow and user behavior for the products		
	<ul> <li>Involved in the process of design and improve API</li> </ul>		
	- Main front-end developer		
	- Mentor new members		
	- Support other members		
	- Review code		
	- Build and set up servers for the products		
	- Merge code and deploy products to servers		
	Angular 8		
Project Technologies	Angular Material		
	Twitter Bootstrap		
	Entities Framework		
	NGINX		
	.Net Core web API		

Microsoft SQL Server
JAVA
MySQL

## Top UK's Recruiter Company - Reed

Position: Full stack developer

Duration: June 2018 – August 2019 Company: Harveynash Viet Nam

Team Size: 22 members

#### Description

For a long time, since 1995, the company has been the best recruiter platform in the United Kingdom. Now they are still one of the best. The company provides a service that connects both the recruiters and the people looking for a job in the most efficient way.

Have been running for a long time, the old service is no longer catch up with the latest technologies and the latest business domains, therefore no longer able to provide the best service for their customers.

A development team is founded to help improve the company's service to be more efficient and able to match with the latest requirements of the new era. The new development team has 20+ members with 2 subteams:

- Recruiter: handing the business for the recruiter to find proper, relevant and suitable candidates
- <u>Jobseeker</u>: handing the business that allows the people to find the correct jobs and companies that they are looking for

#### Responsibilities

As one of the experienced developers with fluent English communication skills, I was put into the Jobseeker team to handle the core business domain directly with the customer.

- Communicate with the customer to get clear requirements
- Breakdown customer's requirements to tickets and sub-tasks
- Refinement and planning for sprints
- Update code according to the ticket's requirements, for the tickets which are assigned to me
- Help and support other team members for their tickets, and for communication with the customer
- Perform unit testing
- Frequently reviewing tickets are done by other team members

	ASP.NET MVC
Project Technologies	REACT, Knockout JS, HTML, CSS, Twitter Bootstrap
	Dapper, NHibernate
	Entities Framework
	Web APIs
	SQL SERVER
	Design patterns (DI/IoC, MVC,)
	CI/CD (TeamCity)

Sitecore Team for an Airline Corporation - Vietnam Airline		
Position: Backend developer		
Duration: January 2018 - May 2018		
Company: FPT Software - FSU1.BU9		
Team Size: 5 members		
Description	The customer is one of the biggest airlines in Vietnam and they are in need of updating their services to be more efficient, the development team is founded to help on updating the technologies on the	
	customer's services so that these can operate more properly and more	
	efficiently.	
	- Study Functional Design Specification	
Responsibilities	- Produce Technical Design Specification, Design Input	
	<ul> <li>Creating UI with Sitecore and MVC</li> </ul>	
	- Coding Web API	
	<ul> <li>Update and manage stored procedures</li> </ul>	
	- Coding Unit Test	
	- Site Core for ASP.NET Webform and ASP.NET for MVC	
Project Technologies	- ASP.NET MVC	
	- ASP.NET Webform	
	- Entities Framework	
	- Web APIs	
	- SQL Server	
	- HTML5 – CSS3	
	- JavaScript - JQuery	

# Sitecore Team for an Energy Provider Corporation - Innogy

Position: Full stack developer

Duration: June 2017 - December 2017 Company: FPT Software - FSU1.BU9

Team Size: 6 members

	The customer is one of the greatest energy corporations in the world. It
Description	is the main energy provider for all countries in Europe. The team is born
	to help the customer to manage their websites in order to:
	- Increase their client's range
	<ul> <li>Provide a better and more efficient way for the clients to</li> </ul>
	approach their services and products
	- Allow the customer to easily control and maintain their
	websites
	<ul> <li>Allow the customer to have better knowledge about their</li> </ul>
	clients (statistic reports)
	- Study Functional Design Specification
Responsibilities	<ul> <li>Produce Technical Design Specification, Design Input</li> </ul>
	<ul> <li>Creating UI with Sitecore and MVC</li> </ul>
	- Coding Web API
	<ul> <li>Update and manage stored procedures</li> </ul>
	- Coding Unit Test
	- Site Core for ASP.NET MVC
Project Technologies	- ASP.NET MVC
	- Entities Framework
	- Web APIs
	- SQL Server
	- HTML5 – CSS3
	- JavaScript - JQuery

Top Singapore's Customs - Cargo Community Network (CCN)		
Position: Junior to Full Stack Developer		
Duration: October 2015 - June 2017		
Company: FPT Software - FSU1.BU1		
Team Size: 8 members		
Description	The customer is a Singapore company which provides cargos shipment and management system for the air cargos industry. Their service is	
	used by many Customs around the world.	
	Their service allows customers to:	
	- Easily connect to all supply chain stakeholders	
	- Access to comprehensive portfolios of advanced IT solution	
	- Simplify the work in cargos management (shipment details,	
	shipment status,)	

	- Efficient in customs security compliance
	- Business performance analytics
	- Study Functional Design Specification
Responsibilities	- Produce Technical Design Specification, Design Input
	- Coding Web API
	- Coding WCF service
	- Coding business logic
	- Create store procedures
	<ul> <li>Coding Unit test script and integrate module</li> </ul>
	- C# .NET
Project Technologies	- ASP.NET Webform
	- Team Foundation Server 2012
	- HTML, Twitter Bootstrap, Telerick
	- JavaScript, Query
	- SQL Server 2012, 2014
	- XAML, XML

# Education

- 1. University of Greenwich Computer Engineering Education Programme Honours Degree
- From 2016 to 2018
- One of few students completed the program on time (straight forward without any retake)
- Degree grade: First Class Honours
- 2. Hanoi Aptech HDSE 2015 Certificate